<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Karthik&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Karthik&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2024, Karthik Ragubathy.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 16:11:39 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Live Coding Setup on Twitch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-live-coding-setup-on-twitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 16:11:39 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-live-coding-setup-on-twitch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been close to 6 months since I started streaming my coding adventures on Twitch. I thought this would be a good time to sit down and write about my experience streaming on Twitch and what I have learned so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers&#34;&gt;Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Till date, I have streamed for roughly 63 hours and have had ~270 hours of content being consumed. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kjevans2787&#34;&gt;Kevin Evans&lt;/a&gt; has been generous enough to subscribe to my stream, and that’s what contributes to a $7 figure (I am rich!). At some point, I aim to donate the money I earn through streaming to some charity, but thanks to the tax rules and conversion rates - it’s quite some time in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fibonacci Sequence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-fibonacci-sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 16:07:05 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-fibonacci-sequence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of late, I’ve been trying to get to the base of how algorithms and mathematics works in general. I’ve wanted to do this for a while because I have an inane fear of Mathematics, and I wanted to face it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was also an effort to deep dive into the fundamentals of Computer Science, a topic dear to my heart, but something I’ve ignored for a while. I chanced upon &lt;a href=&#34;https://teachyourselfcs.com/&#34;&gt;Teach Yourself CS&lt;/a&gt;, a good roadmap for getting started with brushing up your CS fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Career Advice for Students</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/career-advice-for-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 11:24:03 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/career-advice-for-students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At my job, I sometimes get the chance to meet budding student developers. After the workshops, their questions usually revolve around a career in tech and getting started in the industry. I thought it would be a good idea to list down what has worked for me, so I can share it the next time someone asks me for this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before you start reading the post, I want you to keep in mind that I am a victim of confirmation bias. I believe that I was able to grasp some opportunities because I was the right person at the right place at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Into the Voice First World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-journey-into-the-voice-first-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 11:19:49 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-journey-into-the-voice-first-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every now and then, I get questions about opportunities in the Voice First space, and if they can make a career out of it. I thought it would be a good idea to detail my journey so far into the voice first world and the opportunities I came across, to give a broad answer to the questions I get.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Late 2017, after I shut down the company I started - I was keen on being an individual contributor and building stuff myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Experience : AWS Certified Alexa Skill Builder Exam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-experience-aws-certified-alexa-skill-builder-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 11:13:52 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-experience-aws-certified-alexa-skill-builder-exam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If there’s something that brings me back memories of the good-old college days, it is definitely not the exams. From my school days, I do not have a good record of performing well in the exams and that record has extended all the way until the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ets.org/gre&#34;&gt;last exam I gave&lt;/a&gt;, 8 years back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So when my &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/prachimukhija&#34;&gt;manager&lt;/a&gt; encouraged me to get certified in AWS Alexa Skill Builder Exam, I thought it would be a good way to revisit that experience again, albeit with a topic I am slightly well versed with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Curl Fails</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-curl-fails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 10:17:13 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-curl-fails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, as a programmer, you seemingly come upon a problem that flummoxes you, irritates you and takes you through a wide array of emotions - and in the end when you solve it, makes you look back and think, why did this issue even take so much time to fix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s one from my diaries: I was working for a client which dealt with lots of financial data, building an app which dealt with peer to peer wallet system and phone recharges. The app’s backend API was built using a custom PHP framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regexp With Mysql</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/regexp-with-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 10:14:04 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/regexp-with-mysql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In one of the recent projects that I have been working on, I had to look for a word in a phrase - but the challenge was to rank an occurrence of the phrase higher when it’s an individual word as compared to when it was part of a word.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For ex : Food Blogger should rate higher than Ardent Foodie, because in the first example - Food is an individual word as compared to latter where it is part of a whole word.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying With Deploybot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/deploying-with-deploybot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 10:09:40 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/deploying-with-deploybot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I vividly remember the first time, I messed up a production server. It was my early days of being a programmer, and we had got our first client.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back then, my deployment strategy was basically to upload files using FTP and then run any commands on the server via the shell. During a routine deployment, I noticed a file which remained in the server, and in trying to remove it, I typed &lt;code&gt;sudo rm -rf /&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autosaving in Xcode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/autosaving-in-xcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 10:02:09 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/autosaving-in-xcode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While working on a Swift Project recently, I spent ~ 4 hours adjusting a few pop-ups and fine tuning design for a screen. As it so happens, while working in the zone, I missed any committing and committed the code after my entire sprint.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, the other day, I was helping out a colleague with git and explaining git checkout. As it turns out, my brain decided to remind myself of the command exactly while committing and I ended up typing&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
